A Guide to the Bryant Fleming Architectural Drawings, 1913-1942
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Bryant Fleming Architectural Drawings 1913-1942
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
10773
This collection contains 175 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Provenance
This collection was transferred to the Special Collections on July 14, 1988, by Jack Robertson, Fiske Kimball Fine Arts Library, the University of Virginia.
Scope and Content Information
This collection contains 175 architectural drawings, blueprints, and plans, ca. 1913-1942, from the office of New York landscape architect Bryant Fleming, chiefly for projects in New York, Michigan, Tennessee, and Ohio. Also present are drawings and blueprints done for the Finger Lakes State Parks Commission, Ithaca, New York, and Thousand Islands State Parks Commission, Watertown, New York.
Most of this collection is housed in oversize folders but there are two legal size folders of material. This material consists of miscellaneous architectural drawings by various architects other than Fleming, 1913-1921, apparently submitted in some type of competition. The categories of competition include designs of country estates, island yacht club, gardens, motor inns, terminal gardens, central motif gardens, civic expositions, city residences, and an American university. The other folder contains some sketches of "Fernleigh," Cooperstown, New York, belonging to Stephen C. Clark, by Bryant Fleming (1925).
Contents List
- Sketches of "Fernleigh," Cooperstown, New York, belonging to Stephen C. Clark, drawn by Bryant Fleming 1925, Legal Size Folder
- Miscellaneous architectural drawings submitted to some type of competition (by architects other than Fleming) 1913-1921, Legal Size Folder
- Chapin, Roy D., Grosse Point, Michigan, including final plans, elevations, and details of the greenhouse, headhouse, garden, wall, iron handrail, gates, and ironwork 1928-1929, n.d., 27 sheets (Folder 1)
- Allen, Arthur, Nashville, Tennessee, preliminary staking and grading plan 1928, 1 sheet (Folder 2)
- Brown, E.H., Grosse Point, Michigan, garden house 1925, 2 sheets (Folder 2)
- Clements, C.R., Nashville, Tennessee, wall elevation 1930, 1 sheet (Folder 2)
- Dudley, Guilford, Nashville, Tennessee, perspective of house and gardens 1928, 1 sheet (Folder 2)
- Herbruch, C.G., Canton, Ohio, preliminary site study 1923, 1 sheet (Folder 2)
- Scripps, W.E., Orion, Michigan 1926-1927, n.d., 3 sheets (Folder 2)
- Sherwin, Mrs. John, Willoughby, Ohio, details of bird house and sign post 1925, 1 sheet (Folder 2)
- Taylor, B.E., Grosse Point, Michigan, swimming pool house 1922, 5 sheets (Folder 2)
- Tyne, T.J., Jr., Nashville, Tennessee, main entrance gate 1931, 2 sheets (Folder 2)
- Union Building Court, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, general plan and court & bridge sketch 1925, 2 sheets (Folder 2)
- Butler, E.H., Grosse Point, Michigan, garden seat details 1930, 1 sheet (Folder 3)
- Crawford, W., Flint, Michigan, west front elevation n.d., 1 sheet (Folder 3)
- De Waters, A.E., Flint, Michigan, revised details for lamp and standard 1927, 1 sheet (Folder 3)
- Fisher, E., Boston Boulevard, Detroit, Michigan, details of a wall 1924, 1 sheet (Folder 3)
- Hoffmann, Alma, Grosse Point, Michigan, details of console and post 1927, 1 sheet (Folder 3)
- Kausler, Ernest, Grosse Point, Michigan, details of sea wall and profiles of property line walls 1930, 2 sheets (Folder 3)
- Keller, K.I., Palmer Woods, Detroit, Michigan, details of a wrought iron gate to garage court 1928, 1 sheet (Folder 3)
- King, Mr. & Mrs. Leroy, Memphis, Tennessee, details of ironwork for south stairway and east terrace railing 1931-1932, 4 sheets (Folder 3)
- Winter, W.C., Lake Forest, Illinois, details of iron work, tavern table, lattice plant house, masonry construction of the greenhouse and gateway 1930, 6 sheets (Folder 3)
- Cheek, Leslie, "Cheekwood," Nashville, Tennessee, details of loggia, motor entrance, iron arbor, entrance gates, lamp, wrought iron rails, cold frame, vaulting and cornice, curved wall, south garden, elevations and perspectives 1929-1930, n.d., 22 sheets (Folder 4)
- Clark, Stephen C., "Fernleigh," Cooperstown, New York, view from garden terrace and along studio walk 1925, 2 sheets (Folder 5)
- Fort Belvoir, Virginia: Engineer Replacement Training Center, grounds improvement program 1942, 1 sheet (Folder 5)
- Lemon, Brainard, Silver Shop, Louisville, Kentucky 1924, 1 sheet (Folder 5)
- Letchwork Park, Dehagasoh Bridge Perspective n.d., 1 sheet (Folder 5)
- Paine, Nathan, Oshkosh, Wisconsin, headhouse & greenhouse details, sketches for connecting iron gates, loggia, and ironwork, preliminary greenhouse layout, and elevations 1927-1929, 8 sheets (Folder 5)
- Shwab, George, Harding Road, Nashville, Tennessee, garden house construction details 1929, 1 sheet (Folder 5)
- FINGER LAKES STATE PARKS COMMISSION
  - Enfield Glen State Park: entrance portals, identification sign, and planting at upper entrance 1937, 3 sheets (Folder 6)
  - Fairhaven Beach State Park: master plan, landscape plan, electric fixtures, shelter buildings, toilet buildings, main entrance, sewerage system, sign picnic parking, planting schedule, channel and wall, Little Sodus Bay development, and parking area 1935-1938, 19 sheets (Folder 6)
  - Fillmore Glen State Park: identification signs, lower gorge trail, and trailwork in lower gorge 1937, 5 sheets (Folder 7)
  - Robert H. Treman State Park: fish-bearing pond and cliff stairway at Lucifer Falls 1938-1939, 2 sheets (Folder 7)
  - Taughannock Falls State Park: layout plan for tent and trailer sites 1938, 2 sheets (Folder 7)
  - Watkins Glen State Park: entrance revisions, layout plan for upper White Hollow area, terryberry rip-rap wall, White Hollow sedimentary dam, Lovers Lane Trail, Punch Bowl Picnic Site, planting plan-dry wall, rebuilding Rainbow Bridge, south rim road planting, parking area, pool, and plant schedule 1938-1940, 13 sheets (Folder 7)
  - Finger Lakes State Parks Commission General Drawings: double latrine; bubbler drinking fountain; guard rail, table & bench details; and camp cabin 1934-1937, 6 sheets (Folder 8)
- THOUSAND ISLANDS STATE PARKS COMMISSION
  - Cedar Point State Park: detailed planting plans 1938, 1 sheet (Folder 8)
  - Kring Point State Park: master plan 1938-1939, 1 sheet (Folder 8)
  - Watterson Point State Park: picnic ground development 1939, 1 sheet (Folder 8)